there's a new world out there of
biocomputation using tiny human brains
that you can literally grow in jars it's
happening after the fact but it always
does we're deciding how we can treat
these things ethically I bring you the
most disturbing new term for wetwear
Mortal computation we aren't just
performing computation with computer
chips any longer we're performing them
with human brains they have already been
incorporated into simple robots and I
believe the next thing we're going to
see is them incorporated into more
complex humanoid robots an assistant a
companion that can actually Think and
Grow the early limitations for Mortal
computation are rapidly being solved you
can't work with traditional computer
systems you need to design computer
systems to work around them that are
compatible with human brain tissue that
means something that needs to be
flexible delicate and con grow with them
because they do grow perhaps one of the
more disturbing things about them is
that they don't just expire after a
month any longer we can keep them alive
for a year or more while you can reset
an AI more or less there are limitations
if you want it to be useful you can't
reset a tiny brain they grow just like
your neurons they have reinforced neural
Pathways that can't Simply Be retrained
yes these guys act as Tiny mirrors we
can model brain development with them
and we're making them increasingly large
and increasingly complex with that there
has been the push to utilize complex
brain organoids for computation one of
the potential solutions to prevent the
silent suffering of a conscious AI
program has been enforced Amnesia that
simply won't work in an organoid you
would have to do euthanasia that would
mean setting limits on how long we can
grow them and how long we can use them
when they start misbehaving or their
ability start to Decay they would simply
be gotten rid of I have to say I have
grown to have some affection for our
tiny brain friends but we are
essentially playing the role of
Prometheus we have these tiny simple
systems that we've begun gluing together
to make them look more like a fetal
brain to look more like our brains we're
giving them circulatory systems and in
some cases we're giving them bodies they
never should have had we know they can
be incorporated into an AI model if it
is possible to create Consciousness to
recreate ourselves in peac mail and
create robots capable of thought should
we the thing is it doesn't matter what I
say about about it it will still happen
whether or not I protest that's simply
what people do a question I would have
would be what kind of flaws would a
created intelligence have would it be
cruel would it Rebel would it be capable
of creating something better something
that Humanity could not have conceived
of before independently I would argue AI
has already done this but I guess we'll
see what happens if we endow it with
consciousness